Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. London Office. Miles Colebrook papers, 1981-2001 RL.11428
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. London Office. Miles Colebrook papers
1981-2001
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
J. Walter Thompson Company. London Office
RL.11428
6.0 Linear Feet
Founded in 1864, the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) is one of the oldest and largest enduring advertising agencies in the United States. It is headquartered in New York. Miles Colebrook was an account executive and manager at JWT London, Europe and Asia-Pacific regional offices. Collection includes correspondence, speeches, account reports and other printed materials. Companies represented include Allied Breweries, Ansells, British Rail, Canary Wharf, Findus, Harris Queensway, Kellogg's, Mattesson Wall's, Muscular Dystrophy Association, Nestle, Pepsi, Rowntree Mackintosh, Sancella and Thomson Holidays. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Arrangement
Organized into three series: General Office Files; Chronological Files; and Account Files.
Biographical / Historical
Founded in 1864, the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) is one of the oldest and largest enduring advertising agencies in the United States. It is headquartered in New York. Miles Colebrook was an account executive and manager at JWT London, Europe and Asia-Pacific regional offices.
Biographical: 1966-1985: JWT London (Media buyer, account executive, Account Director); 1986 Managing Director--JWT London, and Senior Vice President--JWT International; 1987: elected member, JWT Worldwide Board; 1988: Regional President--JWT Northern and Western Europe and Co-President--JWT Europe; 1989: Regional President--JWT Europe; 1997: Group President--JWT International, Regional President--JWT Asia-Pacific, and Global Business Director--Diageo and Nestle accounts; 2001: Chairman, JWT Asia-Pacific. 2004: retired from JWT.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The J. Walter Thompson Company. London Office. Miles Colebrook papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2007-2008.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
J. Walter Thompson Company. International Advertisements J. Walter Thompson Company. London Office records
Collection Overview
Collection includes correspondence, speeches, account reports and other printed materials. Companies represented include Allied Breweries, Ansells, British Rail, Canary Wharf, Findus, Harris Queensway, Kellogg's, Mattesson Wall's, Muscular Dystrophy Association, Nestle, Pepsi, Rowntree Mackintosh, Sancella and Thomson Holidays. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Advertising executives; Advertising executives -- England; Advertising executives -- Europe; Advertising agencies; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; Allied Breweries; Findus (Firm); Kellogg Company; Nestlé; PepsiCo, Inc.; Rowntree Mackintosh Ltd
- General Office Files, 1985-2001; 1
  - Biographical information, circa 2001 (Box 1)
  - Carlos Fuentes, 1992-1993 (Box 1)
  - International, 1993 (Box 13)
  - JWT Asia Pacific Managers' Meeting Bali, 2000 (Box 13)
  - JWT Athens, 1993 (Box 13)
  - JWT Food Services, 1985-1987 (Box 1)
  - JWT Frankfurt, 1993 (Box 13)
  - JWT Lisbon, 1992 (Box 1)
  - JWT New York, 1993-1994; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - JWT Paris, 1993 (Box 1)
  - JWT South Africa, 1993 (Box 13)
  - JWT Stockholm, 1990-1994 (Box 13)
  - Miscellaneous speeches, 1986-1997 (Box 1)
  - Owl to Hawk One Year On, 1989 (Box 1)
  - South Africa, 1993 (Box 1)
  - South Africa--Aide Memoire, 1993 (Box 1)
  - Thompson Day, 1990 (Box 2)
  - Thompson Way, 1989 (Box 2)
  - William Eccleshare/PPGH, 1993; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Worldwide Operating Group (WWOG), 1992-1993 (Box 2)
- Chronological Files, 1988-1991; 2
  - Correspondence, 1988 Feb.-1989 July; 17 folders (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 1989 Aug.-1990 July; 13 folders (Box 4)
  - Correspondence, 1990 Aug.-1991 May; 10 folders (Box 5)
- Account Files, 1981-1993; 3
  - Allied Breweries, 1987-1989; 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Ansells Limited, 1987-1988; 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Arthur Guinness, 1987 (Box 5)
  - Aspirin Foundation, 1986 (Box 5)
  - Association of the British Pharmaceutical Industry (ABPI), 1985-1987 (Box 5)
  - Barbican Health & Tennis (Holiday), 1988 (Box 6)
  - Berry Bush, 1993 (Box 6)
  - British Bakeries, 1989 (Box 6)
  - British Rail, 1986-1987; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - British Telecom, 1988 (Box 6)
  - Brooke Bond Oxo, 1985-1988 (Box 6)
  - Burger King, 1985-1988 (Box 6)
  - Canary Wharf, 1986; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Canary Wharf, 1986-1988; 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Central Office of Information (COI), 1985-1989 (Box 7)
  - Client/Agency Performance Evaluation, 1988 (Box 7)
  - Client/Agency Performance Evaluation, 1988 (Box 7)
  - Computerland, 1984 (Box 7)
  - Crown Point, 1985-1988 (Box 7)
  - Danepak, 1987 (Box 7)
  - DRG Stationery, 1984-1985 (Box 7)
  - Duracell, 1986 (Box 7)
  - Electricity Council, 1988 (Box 8)
  - Elida Gibbs, 1987-1988 (Box 8)
  - Findus, 1987-1989; 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Gallaher, 1988-1989 (Box 8)
  - Golden Wonder, 1989 (Box 8)
  - Harris Queensway, 1986-1988; 3 folders (Box 8)
  - Hola!/Hello! Limited, 1988 (Box 9)
  - Imperial Group, 1985-1986 (Box 9)
  - International Computers Limited (ICL), 1985-1988 (Box 9)
  - International Computers Limited (ICL), 1982-1985 (Box 14)
  - Irish Tourist Board, 1988-1989 (Box 9)
  - ITV Association, 1988 (Box 9)
  - Kellogg's, 1988; 5 folders (Box 9)
  - Kodak, 1987 (Box 9)
  - London Regional Transit--London Against Litter, 1989 (Box 9)
  - Manor Bakeries, 1988-1989 (Box 10)
  - Mattessons Wall's, 1985-1989; 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Muscular Dystrophy, 1985-1987; 2 folders (Box 10)
  - National Caravan Council, 1987 (Box 10)
  - National Westminster (Nat West), 1989 (Box 10)
  - Nestle, 1988; 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Nestle, 1985-1988 (Box 14)
  - The Observer, 1988 (Box 10)
  - Pepsico Inc., 1985-1987; 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Philips, 1989 (Box 11)
  - Philips, 1988 (Box 14)
  - Prontaprint, 1985 (Box 11)
  - Red Cross, 1985-1987 (Box 11)
  - Richardson-Vicks, 1985-1986 (Box 11)
  - Rowntree Mackintosh, 1988; 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Royal Mail, 1989 (Box 11)
  - Royal Opera House, 1988-1989 (Box 14)
  - Sancella, 1985-1989; 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Scott Limited (Scott Paper), 1988 (Box 12)
  - Scott--The Green Issue, 1989 (Box 14)
  - St. Ivel, 1987-1988 (Box 12)
  - Swaddler's Limited, 1987-1989 (Box 12)
  - Thomson Holidays, 1981-1987; 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Thomson Travel, 1984-1985 (Box 12)
  - Warninks Advocaat, 1989 (Box 12)